<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Critical Techworks Test App</string>
    <string name="title_example">Charles Schwab stock gains after earnings beat expectations, while revenue was a bit shy - MarketWatch</string>
    <string name="read_more">Read more</string>
    <string name="newspaper_app">Newspaper App</string>
    <string name="news_description_example">Charles Schwab Corp.’s stock rose Monday, after the discount broker and financial-services company reported first-quarter profit that beat expectations, while revenue came up a bit short.

Schwab cited “near-record” inflows of capital from investors as it booked more than 1 million new brokerage accounts and $132 billion in core net new assets, including $53 billion in March.

The stock moved up by 2.2% in morning trades.

Chief Executive Officer Walt Bettinger said that while the stock market rebounded during the quarter, equity-investor sentiment “remained bearish,” while the bond markets reflected “growing fears of an economic downturn.”

Net income increased to $1.6 billion, or 83 cents a share, from $1.4 billion, or 67 cents a share, in the year-ago period.

Excluding nonrecurring items, adjusted earnings per share of 93 cents topped the FactSet consensus of 90 cents.

Revenue grew 9.5% to $5.12 billion, just below the FactSet consensus of $5.14 billion.

Total interest-earning assets dropped 20.2% to $504.6 billion.

Schwab’s investor-services unit drew in about $60 billion during the quarter, while its advisor-services unit reported a record first quarter with more than $71 billion in net flows and 70 transitioning-adviser teams.

“These near-record inflows across both our primary businesses represent an annualized organic growth rate north of 7% and helped push total client assets to $7.58 trillion at quarter-end,” the company said. “As investors sought out advice amidst a more challenging environment, net flows into our managed investing solutions grew 26% from the prior year — totaling $8.9 billion for the quarter.”

The stock has tumbled 39% year to date through Friday, while the Financial Select Sector SPDR exchange-traded fund XLF, +0.30% has slipped 3.9% and the S&amp;P 500 SPX, +0.09% has gained 7.8%.</string>
</resources>